



		<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.faircent.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>https://www.faircent.com - i-Learn</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/i-learn</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Decoding the Credit Score: Part 2</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/decoding-the-credit-score-part-2</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faircent Bureau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	While in the previous article, the bare basics of credit score were explained. This installment will further decode your credit score to explain various factors that impact it. Corporate demand for loans has shrunk recently and financial institutions are now focusing more on consumer and personal loan segments. Hence, a good credit score goes a long way to improve the chances of securing a loan at a cheaper rate of interest.&lt;br /&gt;
	To hold a good credit score, individuals need to maintain a thorough credit history which shows up in the repayment track. Depending on your diligence and discipline in repayment, the credit score improves and grades better against those who do not repay timely. Faircent encourages all its borrowers to repay the loans on time and prevent repayment delays as it has negative impact on their financial scorecard.&lt;br /&gt;
	Now, it is essential to understand how the various factors contribute to credit score and what you need to do to keep it as high as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;			&lt;strong&gt;1. The repayment history (35%): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		This is the first and most crucial component that accounts for 35% impact on the credit score. All loans have to be repaid. All bills have to be paid and that too within the stipulated time period without delay to have an impeccable repayment track record. Every single default has a strong negative impact on your score.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;			&lt;strong&gt;2. The amount you owe to lenders (30%): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		The credit utilization has two important factors that determine your ability to secure a loan. Number one is the total credit card amount sanctioned to you and what percentage of it is being utilized. The credit utilization ratio is the balance of outstanding on all credit cards as a percentage of aggregated credit limit on all your credit cards. The loan application becomes riskier as this ratio goes upwards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;			&lt;strong&gt;3. Number of years of servicing debt (15%)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		There is an old saying: A person with on credit history is riskier than person with not-so-good credit history. It might surprise many but the amount of time a person has been servicing debt also contributes to the credit score. This is a very good long term indictor of handling credit responsibly. Hence, the number of years of credit history in conjunction with timely repayments has a positive impact on the credit score.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;			&lt;strong&gt;4. Number and amount of recent loans taken or applied for (10%): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		Every new application for a loan or a credit card etc. leads to financial institutions running a credit check to assess the financial health and repayment behavior. Too many inquires or availing loans in quick succession display a credit hungry behavior and negatively impact the credit score.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;			&lt;strong&gt;5. The Credit Mix (10%):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		This is generation fuelled by EMIs even though we have traditionally been a credit averse society. Avoiding credit like a plague or using only one type of credit line is never a good decision when it comes to positive impact on the credit score. For a positive contribution from this parameter it is helpful to have a balanced mix of secured or unsecured credit lines such as consumer loan, vehicle loan, personal loan, credit card etc. including servicing them timely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;	Now that the components of a credit score have been decoded, it would be helpful in assessing ways to improve it further. Explore areas where you are lagging and use this information to positively impact your credit score. A good credit score contributes a long way to get the loan at the cheapest possible interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 09:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">120 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/decoding-the-credit-score-part-2#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Decoding the Credit Score: Part 1</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/decoding-the-credit-score-part-1</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faircent Bureau In the current Indian economy, credit has played a very crucial role in fulfilling dreams on consumers such as owning a house, car, improving the house and so on. You name a requirement and there is credit available in the market to fund it. Just because someone is willing to lend, it does not mean that you can get the loan. Lending behaviour has evolved over a period of time from checking a borrower’s income to his past repayment history in form of credit score before disbursing funds. Given this scenario, a bad credit score is a crucial reason for not securing a loan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you wish to prevent a last moment rejection it might help to understand the meaning of a credit score, and how to have a good score to establish your credentials. A credit score is an indicator of a borrower’s willingness to repay the loan on time. Loan assessment by a lender is mostly driven by two factor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		1. Ability to repay: That is your income and its utilization pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		2. Intention to repay: Willingness to repay loan. A higher credit score implies higher intention to repay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;	The most popular credit score that comes to mind in India is CIBIL. However, there are three other credit bureaus that evaluate your credit worthiness, namely Equifax, Experian and Crif High Mark. As on date, all credit bureaus provide scores ranging from 300 to 900. An individual with no credit history has a default score of -1. The credit agencies charge a fee to let you access your score. A higher credit score is always desirable. However, different lenders have different risk appetites.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; At Faircent, we classify the borrowers into different risk buckets and we have seen lenders show interest in borrowers across entire risk spectrum. Thus, being a marketplace we allow different lenders to lend as per their risk appetite. However, if lenders are ready to offer loans despite &lt;strong&gt;low credit scores&lt;/strong&gt; then they will charge a &lt;strong&gt;higher rate of interest &lt;/strong&gt;to compensate for risk of repayment. Thus, the loan availed would be a costly transaction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Many times, the lenders do not provide correct information to the credit bureau about loan repayment which can result in a bad score. To ensure that Lenders inform credit account performance across all bureaus and the score is error free, you can raise a dispute resolution with these agencies so that discrepancy in information can be rectified and your credit score  improves. This will enhance your chances of securing loan at a reduced rate of interest, thereby, saving money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 09:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">119 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/decoding-the-credit-score-part-1#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>3 Classic Debt Management Strategies</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/3-classic-debt-management-strategies</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faircent Bureau Have you been feeling overwhelmed by debt of late? If your target is to free yourself from debt then below are three classic strategies to your rescue as per your comfort. However, one thing is very sure: If you do not have a plan then there is no possibility of emerging from this debt spiral. When in doubt, repeat these words: Plan and Budget: follow the Plan, stick to the Budget. Especially and definitely if you have several kinds of debt. Also, if you have a credit card then paying only the minimum debt is not going to ever help – you will choke on interest payments and in the end realize with a rude shock that principal was only a small portion of your entire repayment amount. Without eating your time any further, let’s list out each of the three strategies: 1) &lt;strong&gt;Debt Avalanche Method&lt;/strong&gt; All you arithmetically inclined minds, this is your yummy pie. You swallow the debt with highest interest rate FIRST, as it is costing you most. Literally. Suppose, this was your list of Debts: a)Student Loan: Rs. 5,00,0000 @ 14.25% b)Car Loan: Rs. 1,50,000 @ 10.5% c)Credit Card# 1: Rs.45,000 @ 36% d)Credit Card# 2: Rs. 1,50,000 @ 38% e)Credit Card# 3: Rs. 25,000 @ 30% Using the debt avalanche method, you will focus on repaying Debt# d, followed by c, e, a and b ranked in order of interest rate payouts. Hence, any additional funds out of your financial budget go towards paying off Credit Card# 2 in addition to paying the minimum on rest of your debt. Here, the loan size or loan balances are not taken into consideration. 2) &lt;strong&gt;Debt Snowball Method&lt;/strong&gt; This is your emotional mumbo-jumbo taking precedence. And it is a very crucial factor in fighting debt and helps in winning the all-odds-stacked-against-you-situations. This is a loan size or loan with least balance method. Pick your smallest pie first. Yep, target the loan with lowest balance and hit your first “swift win”. This will give you motivation to pick the next smallest loan and raise your momentum of repayment. Using the above example: Target credit card#3, followed by credit card# 1, Car loan, credit card#2 and finally the big fat student loan. Also, any additional funds out of your financial budget goes to repaying the smallest loan and continue servicing the others as usual. Once the credit card#3 is paid off, hold it, unleash your financial confidence and snowball the payment being made on this debt onto the next debt and so on. The debt repayment would snowball into something bigger with each repaid debt and your worries are going to head further away from you. Acceleration impact! Did we not say that this is an emotional decision that really pays off. 3) &lt;strong&gt;The Debt Snowflake Method&lt;/strong&gt; This is more like a cousin of the snowball method. You might considering opting this if tackling huge amounts of debt gives you shivers and compounding on that is you have irregular income. You take small baby steps towards freeing yourself from debt by targeting smallest loan to largest loan and by paying small but more frequent payments towards your debt. In a bit longish time but surely like a baby you will learn to sprint. Consider this, You can afford to pay Rs. 20,000 towards your debt every month but have an erratic cashflow and hence cannot repay a lumpsum amount. Hence, divide Rs. 20,000 by 4 weeks to Rs. 5,000 per week and start repaying. Diligently. It is going to look less of a burden that way. And we hate to repeat but do it anyway, any additional funds out of your financial budget goes to repaying the smallest loan and continue servicing the others as usual. Also, did you just save Rs. 500 in your grocery bill this week? Did you just find Rs. 1,000 in an old coat pocket?, Did you sell an old microwave for Rs. 1,200 and so on. Take a deep breathe and contribute it all towards the debt you are targeting. Now pat yourself for this achievement! What is essential to understand is that these small amounts add up to a sizeable chunk over a period of time and ease the debt burden for you. Fast forward a few months into the future and you will feel more confident, less burdened and more financially powerful. &lt;strong&gt;Now, which is your method?!&lt;/strong&gt; You might find it odd but all three methods are good depending on your income flow and comfort. It is recommended that you list all your debts in detail, including current balance, rate of interest , minimum payment and tenure. Choose the method which is going to leave you with most satisfaction and motivation in crushing the debt. You could additionally try mixing up these methods and see what works best for you.If adding up the minimum payments leave no room for excesses out of your budget, then you might consider exploring ways to supplement your primary income Caution: Avoid accruing additional debt during this period except during emergencies. The new phone, an additional pair of shoes all avoidable expenditures are a welcome break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-redirect-url field-type-text field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Redirect Url :&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;3-Classic-Debt-Management-Strategies&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 09:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>contenwriter@faircent.com</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">115 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/3-classic-debt-management-strategies#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>How crowdfunding can disrupt traditional VCs and Angels</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/how-crowdfunding-can-disrupt-traditional-vcs-and-angels</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Late last month a significant piece of legislation was passed in the US. The Jumpstart Our Business Startups (JOBS) Act, which was signed into law by President Barack Obama in 2012, finally introduced a rule that now allows anyone and everyone to invest in startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Citizens in the US (known as non-accredited investors) are now allowed to participate in equity crowdfunding and investment in startups and small businesses. The new rules state that startups now have the option to raise either $ 20 million or $ 50 million through two alternate ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	The first option or, Tier I allow startups to raise $ 20 million from ordinary citizens and these companies are not required to perform formal audits and annual reporting. Tier II offerings on the other hand, allows you to raise $ 50 million from the crowd, but will need to have audited Financials and annual reporting of its statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	With regulatory burden significantly lower, the decision to get the crowd involved will have a significant impact on how startups raise funds. We are now in the bastion of angels and venture capital, which have been the mainstay of capital formation for startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	While such provisions are missing from Indian regulatory environment and the crowdfunding industry is itself in a very nascent stage, it is fair to assume that if crowdfunding in its new stage is successful in the US, there would be pressure on replicating it in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Many question if it&#039;s safe for ordinary citizens to invest in risky startups. Of course it is not. However, we must also not question the intelligence of an individual investor, much like we do not question retail investors in stock markets with safeguards on investor protection being put in place. There will be a few heartburns but to me the rule of Caveat Emptor or Let the buyer beware applies. Let an investor know that his investments may come to naught and there are risks involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Tough time for angels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	The biggest impact of crowdfunding in startups will in all likelihood be on angels. Crowdfunding will lower the cost of raising capital, reduce time, investment compliances and fund a wider bouquet of companies. Angels would surely need to adjust their investment model in such a scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	The reason that makes angel investors vulnerable is the fact that most angel investing involves lesser amount of money. Angel investment involves high-risk and the cheque size is generally small. Startups often have to clamor for angel investments as much of the funding happens through word-of-mouth among a network of people and on a local level. Startups outside the system often find it difficult to get access and be noticed. With crowdfunding, startups do not need angels. The same amount or even more can be raised if their pitch works on crowdfunding platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	This also works on another level. Individual angel investors also want to invest in lucrative and interesting startups, but never get to hear about it on time. A crowdfunding platform can be a vehicle that allows them to shuffle through countless startups with interesting ideas. The angel investment market is not as well oiled and established as a venture capital market and sourcing a deal is often a headache for most angels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	In the US, Naval Ravikant&#039;s AngelList has shown the need to have a platform that connects the startups looking to raise fund to angel investors looking to make an investment. Over the short period of its existence, AngelList has ensured that even investors who do not have the tag of a &quot;super angel&quot;, has the potential to make some smart investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	While there are angel investing groups around the world, including India, there are strict frameworks in place that make it difficult for everyone to be a part of it. For example, new members in many angel communities can only be proposed by existing members and in almost all cases have a membership fee attached to it. Crowdfunding has the potential to get everyone investing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Crowdfunding also allows a startup to showcase its acceptability. For an investor, nothing can be bigger than getting a sense of what the general public has to say about a company. By creating a marketplace for an entrepreneur to put his best foot forward, crowdfunding can be the bridge between what deserves to get funded and those looking to make an investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Perhaps the greatest impact would be on startups that do not find favor among the angel investing community and quickly die by the wayside for the want of funds. Startups in spaces like for example creative, arts, music can find a new level of acceptance among members of the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	What&#039;s in store for VCs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	The effect on the VC community, however, is likely to be less radical and may take longer to fructify. Having said that, even in the present form in the US, startups can now raise up to $50 million from the crowd, which is close to what many VCs write for their Series A rounds. The venture industry may feel the heat in the early stages of investing and also smaller VC firms that do smaller investments may take a knock. In India, only time will tell how this shapes up, but a lot of people would beople would be watching the crowdfunding space in the US to pick up the trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Another area where VCs can be hit is that smaller Limited Partners (LPs) may now not feel the need to part with their money and wait for their fund manager to deliver. With a steady stream of startups and ideas available on a platform, LPs may very well choose to invest on their own. There is every possibility that smaller VC firms that do not meet investor expectation find it very difficult to raise funds and ultimately have to fold. VCs funding in India run primarily on money raised from LPs abroad and there is likelihood that they find it increasingly difficult to raise the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	It is unlikely that angels and VCs as we know it will cease to exist. It is more likely that they will migrate to a system them that take into account the crowd phenomenon. A hybrid model where the rules of engagement are quite different from what we are used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Consider this - if from a population of 1.2 billion, about 300 million individuals set aside Rs. 1000 a year for crowdfunding startups, India can create a Rs. 300 billion fund for its entrepreneurs. This will be far in excess of any VC fund devoted to India or any government support scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	We are still in very early days and there is a possibility that there may be some inadvertent mistakes. Democratizing investment in startups and small businesses is a possibility now and chances are we will see a new wave of businesses being created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 12:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">110 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/how-crowdfunding-can-disrupt-traditional-vcs-and-angels#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Budget 2015 should look to enhance access to funds for startups</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/budget-2015-should-look-to-enhance-access-to-funds-for-startups</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faircent Bureau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	The Union Budget for 2015 is less than a fortnight away and this year the government needs to fix vital components of the economy and ensure startups are provided the right atmosphere to grow and flourish. According to me, the budget should address the following five issues on a priority to ensure the country meets its growth targets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Easy access to funding: For every startup, access to funds or capital has been one of the biggest issues and continues to be one. While the startup ecosystem has matured considerably, raising money still continues to be a problem - both equity and debt. With the rise of the angel investing community, a startup can raise some seed money, but funds for growth or to scale is very difficult to come by. India has a clutch of VCs firms and often startups have to jostle around to get a favorable deal. India&#039;s banking system shies away from startups and this only adds to funding woes of a company. While schemes like CGTMSE exists for micro, small and medium industry, the absence of any institutionalized scheme for the startups makes it very difficult to raise collateral free debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Implementation of GST:  Implementation of Goods and Services Tax (GST) has been a long standing demand of the industry. GST will do away with the plethora of taxes that exist in the country, both at central and state level, and come up with a single norm. This would mean Value Added Tax (VAT) at the state level and Service and Excise tax at central level would collapse into a single tax system. For startups, it will greatly reduce the burden of complying with different tax regimes and for entrepreneurs starting up the registration process for indirect taxes becomes a lot simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	GST also has the ability to lower prices as it will rationalize various taxes and also do away with dual taxation of products and services in many cases. New forms of business like ecommerce will significantly benefit from GST implementation as it will bring a uniform tax rate across various states and do away with interstate tax issues, besides removal of a plethora of taxes and cess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Tax exemption for investors: Private money in the form of angels and venture is what drives the startup ecosystem in the country. Most of these funds are from overseas and it is clear investors need incentives and a predictable tax regime to show confidence in the country. In the past retrospective amendments to tax structures created huge distrust among foreign investors and current issues like the Angel tax continue to be thorn in the flesh. Countries around the world have understood that investment is startups are a risky proposition and investors need to be incentivized to put their money and not be taxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	The present regime of Angel tax has proved to be very harmful for the country as a number of startups have shifted base to countries like Singapore, the US and the UK. There is an urgent need to tweak Section 56 of the Income Tax Act to keep startups and the investing community out of this law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Currently, investors are also charged short term capital gains if they sell unlisted securities before three years. This is in stark contrast to what countries like the UK offer where under the Enterprise Investment Scheme an angel investor gets up to 30% tax break in qualifying small businesses and also the Seed Enterprise Investment Scheme that offers up to 50% tax break for investing in very early stage seed and start up businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Service tax exemption for the first 3 years of operations: For every startup that provides a service, a certain percentage (currently to the tune of 12.36%) has to be charged to the customers as a Service Tax. This in turn pushes up the price of the service, which is a bane for most young companies that want to be as price efficient as possible. The pain does not end here as compliance of the tax involves submitting the amount collected to the tax authorities every month and filing a return every quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Currently the threshold for applicability of Service Tax is very low at Rs. 10 lakh and there is an urgent need to increase the level considerably or best exempt a startup for their first three years of operation. Taking out the small ticket firms from the ambit of service tax will allow them to be competitive and at the same time dramatically reduce their time and cost of compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	Reduction in compliance: Presently there is very high cost of compliance even for a small company. As stated earlier compliance around service tax is tedious and complex. Similarly, monthly reconciliation of tax deducted at source ( TDS), paying VAT, CST, excise among many others make compliance a nightmare. There is no unified form to do it and even taking recourse of filing it online is painful. Registers still required to be maintained by the business and are open to inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;	For startups in the manufacturing, life is even tougher in the form of strict labour laws, environmental laws, and various laws under Shops and Establishment Act among others. Startups need all the time and energy they can get and such compliances work as a deterrent. This budget there is an urgent need to reduce the compliance needs of a business and ensure greater ease of doing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 11:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">108 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/budget-2015-should-look-to-enhance-access-to-funds-for-startups#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Need a Loan: 5 Reasons why you must cut the credit card and avail Faircent’s Peer-2-Peer loan</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/5-reasons-why-you-must-cut-the-credit-card-and-avail-faircent%E2%80%99s-peer-2-peer-loan</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;
	Faircent Bureau&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Everybody has lean patches their life when they will be compelled to take a loan and straighten out obligations and expenses until everything falls in place and assumes a normal flow. Unfortunately, a large proportion of people end up relying on credit cards during stressed times because all they need to do is swipe a card and collect cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	There are hoardings, banners, pop-ups etc. vying for attention to take loans on credit cards and no doubt they may have played a role in the past. But, the paradigms have changed. Especially if people require funds for the short term to tackle temporary problems. Faircent has stepped in to provide an online market platform to borrowers to seek loans from a variety of lenders at a mutually acceptable reduced interest rates in comparison to costly credit card options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;1. Faircent Offers Low Interest Rates:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			Firstly, Interest rates charged by credit cards typically hover at 36% because banks and card companies have massive overhead and administrative costs unlike an online P2P platform which is many times cheaper to maintain. High interest costs raise a borrower’s probability of default and leaves a bad mark on credit card users’ CIBIL report leading to further trouble in availing future loans until it becomes a vicious cycle in which everybody stands to lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			On the other hand, a peer-2-peer platform like Faircent pass on their savings on operating costs onto the end consumer resulting in cheaper interest rates and easy EMI Payments.  Secondly, irrespective of your credit-worthiness and excellent credit history, the credit card companies will offer same rate of interest as it does to individuals with bad or junk credit history. However, peer-2-peer platforms take credit history into account which leads to substantially lower interest charged to borrowers with good credit history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;2. Faircent offers Fixed Interest Rates:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			Unlike a credit card which comes with frequently changing variable interest rates, the loan availed from a P2P platform like Faircent is at a fixed interest rate. Holding a credit card debt with an ever increasing interest rate implies an immense amount of worry and uncertainty apart from implied financial loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			Faircent’s &lt;strong&gt;fixed &lt;/strong&gt;and lower interest rate enable the borrower to eventually pay a lesser amount of money during the loan term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;3. Faircent offers Fixed Tenure of Loan Repayment:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			The problem with borrowing on a credit card is that it can push the borrower into a debt spiral since people spend a few months repaying the credit card debt and down the line are tempted to re-use the card which leads to further piling up of the debt with increased charges on the card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			However, at Faircent debt flows in one direction alone. The borrower cannot borrow until all the monthly repayments have been paid in full. This brings better gains financially and mentally for the borrower as it enables them to be debt free at the end of loan tenure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;4. Faircent does not charge pre-payment penalties:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			Credit cards charge a pre-payment fee of 3%-5% on loan amount if a borrower wishes to pay off part or entire debt amount, thereby leaving less incentive to actually pay off debt as soon as possible. However, at Faircent, no pre-payment fee is charged and a borrower can repay the entire outstanding amount at any time during the loan period without attracting additional charges. In addition to reasons above, this leads to greater financial discipline among borrowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;5. Debt Consolidation:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			Typically individuals have different credit cards with different amounts and varying interest rates which can lead to missed payments, financial loss and accompanying negative impact on CIBIL score which is a key determinant on availing loan from banks and financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			Faircent enables its customers to move all debt in one place (not to forget with a lower interest rate) and smoothly ensure one monthly payment to avoid missed/late payments and accompanying charges. Thus, managing finances become comfortable with no hassles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
			It would be essential to point out that most of us use credit cards and they are mostly chosen as a preferred means to arrange for money immediately. They are good “utility” but they come with a great risk for long term credit or debt consolidation and can push a person into a debt spiral. As substantiated above, peer-to-peer loan is a preferable vehicle to enter into long term borrowing or to consolidate high interest credit borrowing at a reduced interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 10:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">81 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/5-reasons-why-you-must-cut-the-credit-card-and-avail-faircent%E2%80%99s-peer-2-peer-loan#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>P2P Empowering the Middle Class</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/P2P-empowering-the-middle-class</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;
	Faircent Bureau&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The last couple of years have been tough for the Indian middle class. Economic slowdown coupled with ever rising inflation has squeezed the finances of every such household. The last couple of decades had witnessed a credit lead growth of the economy, where the availability of cheap credit helped fuel demand generation in the economy. Much of this demand generation was from the middle class which availed home loans, auto loans, personal loans, or relied on credit cards for pacing out their consumption needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The global financial crisis and the rising inflationary trend in the domestic economy resulted in the RBI adopting a high interest regime for over 3 years. This was a double whammy for the middle class, which suddenly faced the twin pinch of rising costs of consumption and rising costs of credit for consumption. Not only were newer loans now much more expensive to avail, but ongoing loan repayment burdens too were suddenly raised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/india-interest-rate.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the wake of these developments, debt restructuring has become important for most middle class households. While some struggle to squeeze out savings to make ends meet, the more industrious type are trying to restructure their debts so as to reduce the interest burden and protect their savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	P2P platforms are one such option, and the service provided by Faircent is fast proving to be one of the top choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/Screenshot%20from%202014-08-06%2011%3A43%3A22.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px; height: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/table-image2_0.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px; height: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The borrower’s profile of Faircent gives a clear reflection of this fact. Majority of registered borrowers are in the age group 20-40 years, which is the early cycle of one’s career. The average salary range from Rs.16000-75000 denotes a middle class income group. A higher percentage in the age group 20-30 years is unmarried, while the higher age group of 30-40 years shows an even share of married and singles. The majority of them live in rented apartments. These are typical profiles of the middle class aspirants planning to settle down and establish a foundation for their future. For the higher age groups, the percentage of home owners and married borrowers rise proportionately, with average salaries well within the middle income range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Most of the borrowers cited debt restructuring as the prime reason for borrowing. The loan percent (total loans sought as percentage of annual income based on declared salaries) for most age group show that the amount sought are not very high proportions of their total incomes. This means that most of them are not borrowing under destitute conditions or are possibly over leveraged. They are simply trying to shift their loan burdens from high interest commitments (possible to conventional financial institutions) to a lower interest commitment, in order to lower the total debt burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	This is where the real benefit of Faircent as a P2P platform lies. It offers borrowers the flexibility to negotiate lower interest rates and reduce interest burdens on their loans. This is a boon for the middle class, as it helps lower their debt burdens while at the same time provides them with cheaper loans to manage expenses in times of high costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The global success of P2P platforms has been on the basis of its popularity amongst the hard hit common man across the world, and Faircent is providing the same relief to their Indian counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 06:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">76 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/P2P-empowering-the-middle-class#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Comparative Earnings: Why P2P is so popular in Developed Economies </title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/comparative-earnings-why-p2p-is-so-popular-in-developed-economies</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;
	Faircent Bureau&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	One of the main reasons for the growing popularity of P2P lending in developed economies has been the rate of returns that investors have been earning. Here is a comparison of the rate of returns from the two major economies, UK and USA, which shows why P2P is gaining such popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;UK&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the UK, the top deposit rate for 6 months tenure is around 1.1% while that for a 2 year period is 1.6%. For 6 month fixed rate bonds, the returns are around 0.9-1.1%, while the same for a 2 year period is around 1.35-1.6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The asset class performance in UK in 2013 for the various assets were as follows: Shares - annual return of 18.23%, housing - 6.9%, bonds had a negative yield of -8.6% while gold too had negative yield of -27.14%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In comparison, among the top P2P lenders in UK, Zopa under its safeguard option offers a return of 3.2%, Ratesetter offers around 3.84%, Ratesetter offers around 4.8-5.2%, rebuildingsociety.com offer a range of 9-9.95%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;USA&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the US, the current CD (Certificate of Deposit, similar to Fixed Deposits in India) rates in banks range from 0.1-1% APY (annual percentage Yields) for a 6 months tenure. A 2 year CD would give a maximum of 0.6-1.26% APY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In terms of other investible assets, the average return for the period 2004-2013 on S&amp;amp;P500 has been 9.1%, 3 months Treasury Bills were 1.56%, while on 10 Year Treasury Bonds were 4.69%. The other lucrative options like real estate and other financial assets have taken a major beating post the financial crisis and have led to major asset loss for many investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In comparison, Lendingclub has a present range of 7.26-12.7% rate of return for loans of 6-12 months, with a median rate of return of 9.9%. Prosper on the other hand, gave returns in the range of 5.65-8.89% across the different risk based classified categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;5%: The new benchmark&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	What is really driving the investment scenario in favour of P2P lending is the steady decline of average investment yield across the most conventional investment instruments. Conventionally, institutional investors like pension funds had 8% rate of return assumption as a base rate. However, the present global scenario has forced a rethink. According to the OECD, the weighted average real net investment return of pension funds which manage combined assets of over $32 trillion was 4.4 percent in 2012, and just 0.2 percent in the year before. US public pension funds,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	who increased the share of equities in their portfolios to try and get the maximum returns, managed an average quarterly return of 3.45 percent in the first nine months of 2013. However, given the high risks associated with equities, there is the threat of corpus erosion and in consistency of returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In this context, the 5% benchmark of returns is a more realistic assumption. The ability of P2P platforms to provide yields at par or even above the best of the conventional investment instruments is the prime driving force for the industry today. Despite obvious dangers of default, the track records of such portals are surprisingly consistent. Lendingclub has an annual rate of default of only 3% while that for Prosper was 8.6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The advent of P2P has revolutionized the investment market for small and medium level investors in the West. The success story seems poised to be replicated now in India as well, with pioneers like Faircent offering similar services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 13:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">73 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/comparative-earnings-why-p2p-is-so-popular-in-developed-economies#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Changing Dynamics of Peer-to-Peer Finance; The Fast Evolving Radical Money Making Option</title>
 <link>https://www.faircent.com/the-changing-dynamics-of-pee-to-peer-finance</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;
	Faircent Bureau&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Even as global markets go shaky and experience volatility making many sweat; it is the Online Direct Lending zone of &lt;a href=&quot;/why-lend&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer finance&lt;/a&gt; that not only remains unfazed, but seems all set to offer some dramatically interesting, money-making opportunities even for those who do not have knowledge of the stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The concept of &lt;b&gt;peer-to-peer lending&lt;/b&gt; is largely internet-based. Offering relatively lower borrowing rates and higher lending returns; this financing option is slowly mitigating the need for banks acting as middlemen between the borrowers and lenders. India too is not untouched by this wave as Faircent.com pioneers in P2P lending in India are introducing the country to a radically new investment option which is easy to relate with, and connect to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Contrary to the scenario 18 months back when the first ever levered fund that invested in consumer P2P loans was launched; there is a notable global shift in the number of those interested in borrowing and lending. Leading lending platforms including Faircent.com now find the balance tilting towards an increase in lenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	While this is a positive sign, there is the issue of deploying all the readily available, surplus investment capital. Also the task does not get easier with (a) institutional investors adding to the competition and (b) the pressing need for portfolio diversification to ensure investment in an array of verticals for best returns. All these issues together have resulted in lending platforms to strictly restrict access at the lenders end and look for borrowers who are relatively more creditworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	However, despite the many challenges monthly loan volumes are experiencing an upswing. According to the editing desk at Equities.com - Prosper and Lending Club both, have seen an increase in loan volumes from $12M and $88M respectively, in November 12, to $77M and $272M respectively, in March14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The present scenario demands developing new opportunities, models and platforms in &lt;b&gt;peer-to-peer finance &lt;/b&gt;and online lending. Some avenues to be explored include - student loan financing, real estate lending, and also financing and lending for Energy Reduction Assets’ development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	With immense potential and growing investment opportunities, the &lt;b&gt;peer-to-peer lending&lt;/b&gt; and finance space is a must-watch right now, especially for those looking for passive means to multiply their earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 05:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">67 at https://www.faircent.com</guid>
 <comments>https://www.faircent.com/the-changing-dynamics-of-pee-to-peer-finance#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
